Minhong (Zed) Zhou Resume

Profile

• Email: minhongz@gmail.com

• Site: https://mhzed.com

• Projects: https://github.com/mhzed

Introduction

I am a software industry veteran with 20+ years of experience. I've worked in environments ranging from startups to established Enterprises. I have realized throughout my career that I love problem solving. The joy of work comes from solving problems and helping others (colleagues, customers, community, etc.) in the process, everything else is just noise. I am an avid learner of new technologies, which comes with the territory of a problem solver. My career goal is to find challenging problems to solve and be useful to others, and I hope my quest for this goal will land me at your company.

Work Experiences

EMC/DELL/OpenText (2012-now)

Senior Consultant Engineer in EMC's ECD division in Shanghai China. Later acquired by DELL and OpenText. Software architect for full text search product development in Documentum xPlore, cloud integration with Solr and ElasticSearch. Experienced in Apache Lucene and its ecosystem of products. Familiar with Natural Language Processing technologies. Chair of China COE (Center of Excellence) patent committee while at EMC.

Ubisoft (2010-2012)

Software lead for the network subsystem of a MMORPG in Ubisoft Chengdu China. Responsible for the server architecture and in game networking subsystem.

AirG (2003-2010)

Server team lead for the mobile social networking product. One of the earliest employees who helped the company to grow from thousands to millions of daily active users. Lead a team of developers to implement a horizontally scalable server farm to handle the traffic.

eCoders (2000-2003)

Self employed. Worked on various software contracts. Developed an online programming competition website.

Internships (pre 2000)

Raytheon, Spectrum Signal Processing, Incognito Software, Wang Laboratories etc.

Education

Bachelor degree from SFU School Of Engineering Science in British Columbia Canada in 2000.

Technical skills summary

- Languages: Java, Javascript/Typescript, C++, Python, XQuery (project), C#, etc.
- Search: Lucene/Solr(demo)
- Cloud: Docker, Kubernetes, CloudFoundry.
- Databases: Mysql/PostgreSQL, MongoDB, xDB(XML database).
- Frontend: React(demo), Angular.
- Deep Learning: WordVec(demo), MNIST(demo). Familiar with NLP, Convolutional Neural Networks, LSTM.